

# **Faisal Rehman**

Phone number: (+49) 1781633786 Email address: faisalfasi18@gmail.com

Whatsapp Messenger: +491781633786

**Website:** <u>faisalrehman-portfolio.netlify.app</u>

O Home: 12049 Berlin (Germany)

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Javascript / React.js / React Hooks / React Router / Redux/Redux-Toolkit / REST API / HTML5 / Tailwind CSS / MUI / Bootstrap / CSS3 / Node.js (basics) / MongoDB (basics) / Git / GitHub / Slack / jira / Adobe Photoshop / Railway / Deployment with Netlify, Vercel / STRAPI / Stripe Payments / Jest/testing-library / Eslint, Prettier / Database: MySQL(basic) / React-Context / Responsive, Cross Browser Development

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

### **Experienced Programmer Transitioning to FullStack Web Development**

I've been programming for over 5 years, have a Bachelor in Computer Science, and currently am at the end of an intensive Fullstack web developer course. I'm comfortable with everything from database schema design to building modern web apps with react and tailwind.

## **Work Experience**

Here are a few recent projects, I've created using React.js, highlighting my expertise in this technology.

Links: https://faisalrehman-portfolio.netlify.app/ | https://fr-netflix-clone.netlify.app

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

#### Web Development

BIT (Beam Institute of Technology) [ 21/11/2022 - Current ]

City: Berlin

Country: Germany

Website: faisalrehman-portfolio.netlify.app

# Web development - Frontend Focused

*Udemy* [ 05/01/2022 - 31/10/2022 ]

City: Berlin

Country: Germany

## **BS Computer Science**

**Hajvery University** [ 01/10/2014 – 30/05/2017 ]

Country: Pakistan

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Freelance Game Developer**

*Upwork* [ 01/02/2020 - 01/12/2021 ]

Country: Germany

- 1. Collaborating with clients to understand their vision and requirements for the game.
- 2. Developing game mechanics, designing levels, implementing UI/UX, and ensuring the game runs smoothly on multiple platforms.
- 3. Writing clean, organized, and maintainable code.
- 4. Participating in code reviews and providing constructive feedback to clients.
- 5. Troubleshooting and debugging issues as needed.
- 6. Meeting project milestones and deadlines.
- 7. Communicating effectively with clients to ensure their satisfaction with the final product.

### **Unity Game Developer**

**BlueHorn Technology** [ 01/09/2017 - 30/08/2019 ]

City: Lahore

Country: Pakistan

- 1. Developed and released a popular mobile game that achieved half million downloads within the first month of release.
- 2. Designed and implemented an intuitive and user-friendly UI/UX system that resulted in increased user engagement and retention rates.
- 3. Optimized game performance to ensure smooth gameplay on low-end devices.
- 4. Collaborated with a team of artists and sound designers to create a cohesive and immersive game experience.

Few links of my games that I developed in this company are given below:

- Dinosaur Game Simulator Dino Attack 3D (<u>Link</u>)
- Dragon Simulator Attack 3D Game (<u>Link</u>)
- Cage Revolution Wrestling World (<u>Link</u>)
- Dress Up Superhero Spider (<u>Link</u>)

### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Urdu

Other language(s):

English German

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1 LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user